[Music]
[音乐]
unbelievable pleasure on a privilege to
能请到 Astro 我感到非常荣幸 请允许我
present my best friend's longtime friend
介绍我最好的 以及长久的朋友 Astro Teller
Google X now x less and general genius
Google X 的负责人 现在叫 X labs
have with what's this with this jacket
这件夹克是怎么回事？
this is just what I put on this morning
我今天早上穿的就是这件
but in fact I got this jacket I think
事实上 我有这件夹克 我认为
someone was trying to prank me they gave
有人可能想整我
me this jacket and I mean in Craig
他们给了我这件夹克 我想
Barrett who at the time also worked at
Craig Barrett 他当时也在
alphabet a matching jacket it wasn't an
Alphabet 工作 一个合适的夹克不是
r2d2 jacket it was a wiki jacket so it
r2d2 的夹克 它是一个 wiki 夹克
had like the bandolier across here and
所以他喜欢上了这里斜跨的弹夹
like the pull up the hood and was all
也喜欢拉起全是毛的帽子
fuzzy and he just said no way I'm not
他说 没门！我不能穿那个去
wearing that's because we were going to
因为我们要在那边花费一天
spend a day I'm seeing an event kind of
我在一场类似的活动上看到他
like this together that he didn't wear
他没有穿那件衣服
it and I just thought you know it's a
你知道的 我只是想
little bit lame I I'm gonna wear my r2d2
这有点差劲 我要穿我的 r2d2 夹克
jacket so even though I mean I'm into
所以 我的意思是 我喜欢《星球大战》
Star Wars but I'm not super into Star
但也不是超级狂热地喜欢《星球大战》
Wars but if I work for the day just for
我只是想为喜欢的事工作一天
fun I don't know and then I got into it
我不知道 然后我来工作了
I'm just enjoying being a robot i guess
我猜我只是很喜欢当一个机器人
i guess they were you robots just
你猜你是机器人？
kidding but you just joined us as a
开个玩笑 但是你成为了我们的招聘合作伙伴
think this became the best place to walk
我认为来硅谷工作是最好的选择
well we hired lots of things we're
我们招聘的职位有很多
certainly hiring roboticists we care a
显然 我们在招聘机器人专家
lot about machine learning a lot of the
我们十分关心机器学习
work that we do at x is systems
我们在 X 做的很多工作就是系统整合
integration work we don't do a lot of
我们并没有做很多基础性科学工作
and so a lot of that turns out to be
所以 很多复杂的迭代系统集成性工作
kind of work taking pieces that already
有时候 他们所制定的传统版本 需要被用不寻常的方式整合起来
getting it out in the world trying
你得到它 尝试它 并证明你做错了
you've discovered that you're wrong and
然后你做了一个新的设计 再尝试
sort of general way that it feels I
我想 这是 X labs 的项目的一般模式
people who are good at that I want it I
所以 这里的人很擅长这个
want it I want to take you 50 years in
你觉得 50 年后 世界会变成怎样？
tossing let's go I don't obey this law
棒极了！我们走吧！
I ideas I think the world is going to be
因为我认为 20 年后世界就会大变样了
a bad I'm sure it'll be a mix i think
我确信喜忧参半 我认为很大概率上在大多数好的地区会让人激动
mostly positive place i'm sure it's
我相信中间的道路不会明确
they'll talk about a nuclear winter i
很多人觉得会有世界范围的核战争 导致核冬天
don't know i think that the world is
我不知道 我认为这个世界的积极因素 比我们以为的更多
positively than negatively but the world
世界会走过一个非同寻常的20年
years the saying is and i think that
这就是说 我认为人们倾向于高估短期的技术进步和改变速率
that is three years from now they think
未来3年内 他们认为世界将和现在变得大不相同
it is and they underestimate it in the
但他们低估了在中期 也就是10~20年的变化
we all collectively can't really imagine
我想 我们都很难想象会有多大不同
the past so if you can imagine the last
所以 你想象一下过去100年的变化 和接下来20年的变化
I think that that's probably a realistic
我认为这是一个较为现实的估计 估计未来的世界会有多大不同
wow that means people have to have done
这意味着人们需要学习很多东西
experiencing well I think it always
你身上有一件事让我印象深刻
you celebrate when you fire people over
当你解雇一些人的时候 你会庆祝一番 是这样吗？
mean i'm not sure we would celebrate
是的 我是说 我不确定我们会让其他人去做什么
letting someone go though sometimes it
可是有时候在一些情况下
is the case that we helped people to go
我们帮助人们
to a place that is better for them and i
去一个对他们来说更好的平台
have at least on occasion had them
我至少说是提供一些机会给他们...
deliberate them yes absolutely it is
释放他们 绝对是
sometimes the case that you know Susie
比如如你所知
can be great somewhere but the place she
苏西可以在另一些地方做的很棒
currently is is not where she can be
但是她现在所在的地方并不好 把这个告诉她
great and it is a favor to Susie's team
这对苏西的团队和我也有好处
and to myself but also to Susie to tell
对她自己也有好处
that to Susie certainly not telling her
当然不告诉她
that and letting her just suffer
让她承受当她的能力出色到
indefinitely being not excellent when
可以完成更好的任务时
she has the capacity to be excellent
却还要一直去做不出色的事
it's not doing anybody particularly
这并不是在帮任何人忙 特别对苏西而言
Susie a favor he doing despite a baby
顺便说一下 你对我们所有的学生都这样
auto students the clear liberating all
释放所有的人的潜力？
of them you can be graduate them yes
- 你可以让他们所有人毕业 - 是的
well I didn't anything with our projects
我对我们所有的项目都做同样的事
yes yes Stanford doesn't remember we
是的 斯坦福还是 不记得这些了...
have these wonderful pompous moment
我们送走每个学生时
seven we take out every student I think
所拥有的美好的时光
the parents come just elevator with him
我想起他的父母与他一起乘电梯过来
about this feature that's why we call a
这就是为什么我们
graduation for the project and X so
称之为毕业项目
instead of feeling like they're being
X 不会让他们觉得
kicked out of Eden they feel a little
被踢出了伊甸园 他们会有一点背井离乡
going to college hopefully i skeeve
- 和充满希望上大学的感觉 - Steve Blankie
blankie before a NASA does want a
前美国宇航员 想问一个问题
question and I want to ask you the same
我也想问你同样的问题
question um I want you to go back to
我想让你
your 18 years 18 years old self when you
回到18岁 当你刚进入大学
just enter in college what advice would
你对自己有什么建议
you give yourself you know one of the
你知道的
things that I think about frequently if
我经常想的事情之一就是
I could go back and change something it
如果我能重回 18 岁并改变一些事情
was a little moment but it's become
哪怕只是一小段时间
actually bigger for me over time instead
但它实际上对我来说很多 而不是很少
of smaller I was a junior so maybe nine
我是一个大三学生 也许有二十来岁
twenty-something what 20 years old
大概在斯坦福大学
probably at Stanford and my brother had
我弟弟刚来斯坦福大学
just got into Stanford he was a freshman
他是新生
he was doing an undergraduate degree in
他正在读物理学学士
physics but he was spending actually
但他实际上花了更多的时间在演艺事业上
more of his time doing acting being a
成为一个舞台人物
thespian than being doing his physics
而不是攻读他的物理学学位
degree and I was getting to know his
我正好认识
mentor whose name's winter Meade and
他的导师 Winter Meade
after one of the show's winter came up
一次表演之后 Winter 来找我并说
to me and he said you'd be great in the
你在剧院会更加成功
theater you should really join the
你真的应该加入一家公司去做点什么了
company and do something and I said oh
我说 哦不
no I'm really busy I had some set of
我真的很忙 我有一堆借口
excuses and I was really busy that's not
我当时真的很忙
why i said no i was afraid i just i
那不是我说不的理由 我很害怕
don't know i think was probably because
我只是不知所措
it was important to me and I've
我想可能是因为那对我不是真的重要
regretted that ever since not because I
从那以后我很后悔
want to be in the theater it just
不是因为我想进剧院 这只是很困扰我
bothers me it's one of the few things in
这是少数几件我生活中没有做的事
my life I didn't do because I was afraid
因为我害怕
and I know I didn't do it because I was
我也知道我没做它是因为我害怕
afraid and I thought ever since i'm not
自那以后我想 我不再做那个了
doing that i can fail for all kinds of
我可以以各种各样的原因失败
reasons but i'm not going to fail again
但我不会再失败了
cuz i was just too afraid to try so now
因为我害怕去尝试
when you afraid you do it yeah I am
所以当你害怕时 你会这么做？
actually counter phobic and how can you
是的 我事实上抗拒恐惧...
drive a car I'm not afraid to track a
你怎么来开车 事实上我不怕追踪一个车
car I really actually but I'm not yet to
但是我还没有闯过红灯
run a red light different story you've
不同的故事 你已经做了
done an unbelievably amazing job as the
在硅谷中都是一项
queue of Silicon Valley the magician who
令人难以置信的工作了
puts balloon into the stratosphere still
你像魔术师一样将气球放入平流层
self-driving cars and whatever it is
你在 X 中做过自动驾驶
that you've been doing in X what is your
或者其他的什么
vessel thank you too and maybe I take a
什么驱动着 X 这艘大船
tiny bit of credit as well but what's
也许我可以拿我的一点点信用
your recipe no so true to this
但是你的秘诀是什么 看起来感觉很不真实
organization evolves and matures and
这个组织发展并成熟 坦白来说
quite frankly gets larger in size to
规模更大而且能够与时俱进
keep it fresh how do you keep like the
你怎么保持你的
innovative genes going I think a lot
创新基因持续呢
about all the tensions that we have at X
我想到很多在X中的矛盾和难题
and some of the tensions are fairly
其中的一些相当简单
straightforward some of them less
其实一些则并不简单
straightforward but for example we have
但是 例如
to have raging optimism or we would
我们必须有极为乐观的态度
never try the things that we try but if
或者我们不会尝试所有的事
you just
但是如果你
power people have raging optimism go
只是让人们肆意乐观
forth be crazy the crazier the better
那么出门 疯狂去吧 越疯越好
without limit you are not going to get
没有限制 你不会得到好的结果
good results so there has to be a kind
所以必须有一种
of scathing paranoia and skepticism that
令人沮丧的偏执和怀疑态度
balances out that optimism you have to
才能平衡这种乐观
keep those in balance if you're actually
如果你想得到你想要的
going to get what you want but that's
你必须保持平衡
not the only kind of tension that we
但是那不是我们拥有的唯一一种紧张局面
have another one is the you know what
你知道另一种
you could say positively would be to
你可以说乐观将会
support structures at X or if you want
支持 X 的结构　或者你想否定它
to be negative about it the bureaucracy
因为 X 中的官僚主义
at X so we want to bring to bear on
所以 我们想要在
projects the right help at the right
正确的时间对项目进行正确的帮助
time to amplify them or to help you know
详述它们或进行帮助
move them on to a better path when
在他们完成项目时
they're sort of veering off of the path
保证不偏离正确的轨道
in the best-case scenarios that's
在最佳的情况下 这
wonderful of course it sounds really
很棒 当然它听起来真的
positive the way I just said that but if
很棒 像我刚刚说的那样 但是如果
it's done wrong it sure feels like
它做的不好 那么一定看起来像
bureaucracy to the project leads and
官僚主义的项目负责人 以及
they sometimes express that to me and
他们有的时候会告诉我
the bureaucracy is the last thing that I
官僚体制是最后一个我
want to produce so that's another
想制造的 所以这是另一个
example where having no structure
例子 那些无结构的
doesn't make any sense then we're just a
也是无意义的 所以我们仅仅是
venture capitalist we're just giving
风险投资者 我们只是给予
people money and walking away that
人们金钱并走开了
actually makes sense for us to do that
那么这对于我们做这件事是没有任何意义的
but if we smother them with attention if
但是如果我们紧紧勒住他们
I think that I know how to do their job
如果我认为我知道如何把他们的工作
better than them one of us is redundant
实现的比他们还好 那我们中的一个肯定是多余的
like that's a bad plan so getting that
看起来是一个糟糕的计划 所以轻微的接触
light touch is another example where it
是另一个例子
both ends of the spectrum are bad and
两个极端都不好
there's somewhere in the middle that's
中间的平衡点
right and we're always sort of searching
是我们一直寻找的正确的地方
for it many a lot of students and
>>很多学生和
partners came from I think over 20
伙伴来找我 我认为超过20个国家
countries it is amazing including places
这很令人惊讶 包括了
as always Jordan Estonia what is the
像约旦、爱沙尼亚这些地方 硅谷的魔力是什么
magic of Silicon Valley and what can you
对于不同国家的人
take home for different countries
你又能把什么带回家
there's something in the water here
>>如果说这里的水有什么东西的话
that's certainly palpable I think for
我认为可以肯定的是人
the people at engler take I'm not
事实上
actually suggesting taking the water
我不是真的建议你把水带回家
home you know what
你是知道的
one of the ways that is not my favorite
其中一种方式 尽管不是我喜欢的措辞
phraseology but I've heard it frequently
但我已经听了很多次的
is a culture of creative destruction and
是一种开拓性的创造文化
so that's not what I would take home but
所以这并不是我要带回家的
I think that that's what you might hear
但是我认为你可能已经听到了很多次
frequently one of the ways i might
其中有一种方式我可能更喜欢
prefer it would be a healthy embrace of
请乐观的拥抱失败
failure so someone was just asking me as
所以一家韩国的报纸
a korean newspaper as asking me how can
问我怎么才能让
the companies in Korea do better they
公司在韩国做的更好
feel really afraid to take risks because
他们真的是害怕去承担风险因为
they might look bad and I don't know
他们可能会看着很糟
this is true but this was a suggestion I
我不知道这是否是真的
gave yesterday morning to this reporter
但是这是我在昨天早上
to take back to companies in Korea which
请一位记者带给韩国公司的建议
was it's not that we want to look bad in
我们并不是想在硅谷看到这不好的结果
Silicon Valley I don't think that's it
但是我认为并不全都是这样
at all but I'm willing to look
但是 我愿意现在看起来是愚蠢的
arbitrarily stupid right now if that's
如果是从长远来看
what it takes to win in the long run I
会赢得胜利的话
think it's a time horizon difference if
我认为这是一个时间差异
you understand and can connect that
如果你明白并可以理解学习的本质
being open to being wrong now is the
是对错误保持开放的心态
essence of learning and that learning is
学习是导致你获胜的
the superpower that causes you to win
最强大的力量
then you become hungry to be wrong and
然后你渴望错误 并重新开始
to start over and to try new things now
迫不及待的去尝试新事物
no matter how imperfect it makes you
不论在短期内你看起来是如何的不完美
look in the short term because your time
都没有关系
horizon on which you're unwilling to
因为你不愿意输掉的时间范围更长
lose is very long and so I think even
并且我认为
though there is a culture of speed in
尽管在硅谷有一种追求速度的文化
Silicon Valley I believe that the length
但是我相信人们
of the time horizon over which people
试图让自己变得更好的
are trying to optimize themselves being
时间维度可能会拉的更长
longer may actually be part of the
这可能也是秘诀
secret sauce we have microphones and I
我们有麦克风
want to open up for audience question in
我想要给观众几个开放问题
a minute so if you want to line up
你们可以像以前一样
between these two microphones piece as
两个麦克风排队
usual but I have one question by
我有一个问题
dividing up tell us about his son like
希望你告诉我们你儿子的故事
so he's referring to the fact that my
他指的是我儿子一年多以前
son finished his first nanodegree a
已经完成他的第一个纳米学位了
little over a year ago his name is
他的名字叫 Griffin teller
Griffin teller and he did the
他完成的是
introduction of computer science he
计算机科学导论
really enjoyed it he was
他很喜欢这个
just during 12 when he finished it and
他在12岁的时候完成它的
he's struggling his way here working
他十分努力的完成它
hard and our little struggling might not
一点点小的挣扎不是恐惧
be fair even through the machine
即便是机器学习课程
learning course and i just had
我刚刚..
sebastian's I told Sebastian this over
上周晚餐告诉他
dinner last week and he said oh that's
他说
actually one of the really hard courses
那门课真的蛮艰难的
and I went home they said you know
我回家说 你知道的 Griffin
Griffin you're going pretty slowly
你通过它花了很久
through it Sebastian says that's one of
Sebastian说
the really hard ones you want to ask for
这个课程真的很难
help do you want to switch to one that's
你想要寻求帮助吗？你想要换一个简单的嘛？
easier he's like no no I got it I
他喜欢这个 不 不 我选了这门了 我只是...
justice I have to like go back and like
我必须坚持下去
learn a whole bunch of extra mass every
每到下一个阶段 都要学一大堆额外的数学课程
time I get to the next stage 13 now so
他现在13岁 所以..
but I'm very very grateful to Udacity
但我非常感谢 Udacity
because Griffin's a brave boy and he's
因为 Griffin 是个勇敢的男孩
hard-working and he's focused but that
他很努力工作 也很专注
by itself i was just saying back in the
但这本身就是在
green room wouldn't actually have
这绿房子里说
translated to something like this i
实际上并不是这样的
don't think it's an accident that he's
我不认为这是一个意外
not doing chemistry or physics or
他不是在做化学或者物理或者历史
history there isn't a platform for
没有一个支持他的平台
supporting him doing that and Udacity
Udacity 实际上已经
has actually provided him with just the
给了他正确的结构
right kind of structure so he has to
所以他必须努力
work hard he can self paces learning it
他可以自学
means a huge amount to him you should
这对他意义重大
actually part of why I'm here today yeah
这也是我今天为什么在这
we have over 20 recruiter both sides and
是的 我们有20多个招聘人员
I think you should bring him here and
我想你应该把他带到这里和他们聊聊
coke again excellent otherwise over
棒极了 否则就会超过学费了
tuition tax this start in the center
让我们从中间开始吧
hello dr. teller could you perhaps share
你好 Teller 先生
a little bit about the use of
可以分享一些关于对冲基金在
reinforcement learning in hedge fund
强化学习中的用法么？
reinforcement learning in which domain
强化学习的哪个领域？
in hedge fund or financial hedge fund
- 对冲基金或财务 - 对冲基金
I'm not sure reinforcement learning is
我不确定强化学习是...
the only issue let me answer or
一个问题 让我更全面的回答你的问题
generally the time I believe where the
我相信目前在许多领域
application of machine learning in many
应用机器学习的方式
domains to the individual problems as
那么人类所构成的
posed by humans is ending it'll go away
问题将会结束 它会消失
over you know 10 or 20 years it won't
你知道的 10年或20年
happen overnight the thing which is
它不会发生在一夜之间
starting to be the case and one of the
事情开始是这样
areas in which you can see this
你可以看到它
happening is hedge funds is where the
发生在对冲基金领域
questions themselves are being asked by
这正是机器学习问题的
machine learn
本质所在
now it often won't look like and machine
现在它往往不会像机器学习一样
learning being you know deep nets and
你知道深度网络和强化学习
reinforcement learning and a number of
以及其他一些工具
other tools it's sometimes won't look
有时不会像问题被问道
like the question is being asked but
但是当您在任何领域中
when you do end-to-end learning of any
进行任何形式的端到端学习时
kind in any domain you are essentially
你基本上都会离开系统
leaving up to the system that's doing
这正是在学习
the learning more of the decomposition
更多的是将问题分解到计算机
of the problem to the computer to the
到学习系统
learning system that that's part of the
这是任务的一部分
task the feature izing of the data the
将数据功能化 分解问题
decomposition of the problem that's what
这是人类以前做的
humans used to do and so I think that
所以我认为这些行为是
movement is something we're going to see
我们要看到更多的东西
a lot more of at computers essentially
更多的是开始问问题
starting to ask the questions and
和计算机基本结构
structure the problem as well as
相关的问题
actually solving the problem and hedge
这实际上就是在解决问题
funds is definitely one of the areas in
而对冲基金绝对是发生这种情况的领域之一
which that's happening all right thank
好的 谢谢
you so much would you summarize your
你可以总结下你的失败观么
view of failure on failure as fail fast
在失败这件事上 失败得越快 学习得越快?
learn faster yeah I mean fail fast is
是的 我的意思是
lip service which is thrown around very
快速失败是口头上的
liberally all around the valley and
如同绕着山谷和其他地方快速抛出
other places and I think it largely does
我认为它在很大程度上不会知道人们想要什么
not get people what they want and so
所以这个术语 失败准确
there's something wrong with the term
没有任何错误
fail fast but that and the dollar fifty
但是50美元可以让你上公共汽车
will get you on the bus the problem is
问题是正如失败快一样
that there's the lip service of whatever
你说的只是口惠
you say like fail fast and then there's
然后实际上是人们真实做的
the actual way that people behave and
这些指针如此
the reason that those pointers are so
不同的原因
different is because these are the
在于你的组织中有
emotional paths of least resistance in
阻力最小的情感路径
your organization and you can say fail
你可以等到奶牛回了家才说快速失败
fast until the cows come home but if you
但是如果你惩罚被人
punish people in fact if you do anything
事实上如果当他们失败时
short of actively rewarding them when
你做了任何事积极回报他们
they fail it doesn't matter that you say
那么你说快速失败并不重要
fail fast so what do you mean it when
所以 当你再谈论快速失败时
you say fail fast and so we have
你是在谈论什么呢？
mechanisms at X to reward people when
在我们 X 有回报机制
they stand up and they say that was a
他们说 这是我们刚刚跑的有价值的实验
worthwhile experiment we just ran and
以及 实验的结果
the results of the experiment is the
是零假设
null hypothesis ie we shouldn't keep
例如：我们不应该做这个
doing that great let's go on to the next
太棒了！让我们进入下一步
one you reward them in that moment you
你在那一刻奖励他们
don't punish them for admitting that the
你不要惩罚他们在
result of the experiment was the null
试验中所得到了 0 假设的结果
hypothesis that's often the answer
当你进行实验时 也很容易得到这个答案
run an experiment but that's not how
但这不是
most corporations work that's not how
大多数公司的工作方式
people feel when they go to work in the
这不是人们早上上班的感觉
morning they want to get an atta boy
他们想在伙伴中找到一个男孩
from their peers they want to get an
如果他们说了
atta boy from their manager if they
“我的程序没有起作用”
can't get one by saying my thing didn't
而得到他
work they will not say my thing did not
他们将不会再说了
so add a question so does moonshots work
添加一个问题 登月是否可以解决
on problems like starvation and hunger I
饥饿问题 我是说
mean can we ever solve real problems
我们是否可以使用技术
today with technology like starvation
解决这些真实问题？ 就以饥饿为例
hunger as an example sure I don't have a
当然 我还没有准备好
ready solution for starvation and hunger
一个解决饥饿的方案
but I don't think that any problem is
但是我不认为有问题可以阻碍有关登月的思考
immune to moonshot thinking so at least
至少我们会在X项目
the way we would define it in X a
中定义这种方式
moonshot has three basic components
一个月球探测器有三个基本元素：
there has to be a huge problem with the
这是一个真实的问题
world that you can name and you want to
你可以定义它 你想要解决它
address you have just named a huge
正如你刚刚所指出的我们世界存在的
problem in the world the second is you
一个巨大真实的问题 第二点是
have to have a radical proposed solution
你必须要有一个激进的解决方案来解决这个问题
to that problem not radical because you
不激进是因为
want to be cool and get cool points in
你想变得很酷 找到那些
the world for having been weird but in
很奇怪的点子 但是
the spirit of trying to go to a new
去尝试一个新地方
place to try something that people
尝试人们没有尝试过的东西
haven't tried to not just be in a
这不仅仅是一个聪明的比赛
smartness contest with everyone else
其他每个人都想
who's tried to address the problem but
解决这个问题
to be in more of a bravery and
但是更富勇敢和创新的内容
creativity contest with the problem
聚焦于问题本身
itself so that's the second thing having
所以 这第二点就是
a radical foreclosed solution and then
有一个彻底的解决方案 然后第三点是
the third at least as we would define it
我们至少要定义它
but I suppose there other ways of
但是我想有其他方法修补问题
dressing problems but EDX we would say
但是在 X 我们必须有
that the third problem the third aspect
第三个方面
that you have to bring in order for it
你要制造一个月球探测器
to be a moonshot is you have to present
你必须提出一些
some kind of breakthrough technology or
有突破性的技术
proposed set of technologies which
或者提出一个突破性的
brought together would be a breakthrough
技术组合
that would enable this science-fiction
这将会使得这个听着
sounding product or service that would
像科幻小说的产品或服务
solve that problem put in that way
最终可以解决问题 以这种方式
there's no reason that you couldn't
没有理由利用这些工具
solve starvation and hunger using those
还解决不了饥饿问题
tools and I hope you do thank you you
我希望你理解了 谢谢
just described some of the criteria for
你刚刚描述了一些
what makes a good project but where do
好的项目的标准
the projects come from originally and
但是项目从哪里开始
how do you go through vetting
如何通过审查
them and forming like a more long-term
并形成一个长期的项目
project so i could imagine other ways of
所以呢 在 X 大概是这个样子
doing it roughly the way it feels that x
实现一个项目会有一个虚拟的表
is there's a huge pile of ideas on the
表上列举出一堆有关这个项目的想法
metaphoric table anyone can put them on
任何人都可以把他们的想法
the table and by the way we have a
加到这张表里 顺便说一下
mechanism where you guys can submit on
我们有一个机制 你们可以在我们的网站上提交
our website moonshot ideas to X and
有关月球探测器的想法给 X
we're very happy to take them from any
我们非常高兴可以带他们去任何地方
in all places because we believe that
因为我们相信他们的想法
ideas by themselves raw technologies by
粗略的技术
themselves they're worth something but
确实是值得的
they don't reliably turn into something
但是他们还不能把这些变成真正伟大的事情
great that the work that's really
真正的特殊工作
special happens primarily after the idea
发生在这个想法之后
so we have this huge pile of ideas on
所以我们在表里面有这么多伟大的想法
the table there isn't an actual table
这只是一张虚拟的表
right and then a lot of the fail fast a
很多想法失败了
lot of the work is how do you pick
大量的工作是尽可能
through all these things on the table
多的挑选一些想法
and throw them away as fast as possible
并尽快筛掉其中不合适的
as efficiently as possible but for good
但是要为了好的原因
reasons not for fake reasons if you're
而不是虚假的理由
like I don't like that one it's easy to
你就像我不喜欢的那个
take it off the table but you haven't
从桌子上拿开很简单
actually added any value that's not a
但是你没有真正为它附加价值
good reason if you pick one off the
这不是一个好原因
table and you say hey look this one
如果你从桌子上挑了一个　你说 嘿 看
breaks the second law of thermodynamics
这违反了热力学第二定律
I think we can throw that one away
我认为我们可以把它丢掉
without further discussion oh look this
而无需任何讨论
one is made of unobtainium right so we
看吧 这是由难得矿素构成
can throw that one away sadly not all of
是的 我们可以把那个丢开 难过的是
them can be removed from the table as
不是所有的这些都可以从表里轻易的移除
easily as those and so you often have to
所以你要经常做真正的工作
do real work sometimes you have to build
有时候你必须建立原型
prototypes you have to talk to the
你必须和那个处
people who act in that ecosystem and say
在生态系统中的人交谈
if we built this thing would it solve
如果我们这么做的话会解决问题吗
the problem and then they say not really
然后他们说 不行
well that's good to know thank goodness
我们没有为了建立那个而
we didn't spend a huge amount of time
花费大量时间和金钱
and money building the thing only to
仅仅在最后发现
discover at the end that that wasn't
并没有真正解决
really going to solve the problem in the
这个世界上的问题
world so that is one of the main muscles
所以这是 X 的主要准则之一
at X is how do you get people both to
你如何让人们感觉良好
feel good about throwing stuff on to the
并把想法加入到表中
table and feel good about taking it back
并把想法从表中取回
off the table and the best-case scenario
最好这些事是发生在一次会议中
which has happened a few times that X is
这已经在X中发生了几次了
when the both happen in the same meeting
当有人想从我这里
when someone gets a brownie point from
或其他人那里获得印象分
me or from others for having brought up
并在相同的会议中提出了
a beautiful idea and in the same meeting
一个不错的点子 并迅速否定
throw the idea way and gets two pieces
这样就得到了两份印象分
of brownie point that's failing fast
这就是所谓的快速失败
when they feel like they got brownie
当他们觉得因为把这想法
points for putting on the table and
放到表里而得到印象分之后
taking it off in a half an hour meeting
会在半个小时的会议中把它拿走时
so I was about to pass this question but
所以 我即将通过这个问题
then when you said that don't regret it
当你还在说你明天不会后悔的时候
tomorrow that's why I came in here good
这就是为什么我来这里 好
so both of you are people who have
所以你们都是那种
created the kind of impact which
每个人都希望在
everyone here wants to create in their
他们生活当中创造影响力的那种人
lives but my question is that suppose
但我的问题是 假设你有一个像我这样的人
you have a person like me I have figured
我明白了我的激情
out that this is my passion this is the
这就是我想要解决的问题
problem I want to solve but along the
但在另一方面
side I need to stay relevant I need to
我也要保持变化
know the current affairs I need to know
我需要知道现在发生的事情
like read TechCrunch wired Business
我需要阅读诸如科技博客、连线、商业内幕消息
Insider there's like so many resources
这里每天会创造
and all of them creating so much new
很多资源和很多信息
information every day that if I spend
如果我每天花很多时间阅读这个
time reading those I won't solve my
我就没时间解决我的问题
problem I won't be doing my job so my
也没时间完成我的工作了
question to you is along with following
所以我的问题是
your passion how do you spend your time
如何遵循你的激情来安排你的时间
and keep yourself updated so not you
并让自己不断提高 所以这个答案
know these answers will be probably
可能会受你们欢迎
popular with you guys but not popular
但在世界其他
with much of the rest of the world but I
地方可不会 但是我对这两个因素
feel pretty strongly about both of them
都很看重
the first one is I got lucky I won't
第一个是我很幸运
speak for Sebastian but I got lucky and
我不会为塞巴斯蒂安说话 但我很幸运
I I hope that you guys are calibrated on
我希望你们是这样认知的
that that the people who are the most
那些最成功的人通常
successful usually worked fairly hard
工作的相当努力
and they have some skill that wasn't
他们有一些技能 不完全依靠幸运
entirely luck but do not believe that
也不相信拥有
there is not a huge amount of luck
或获得很多幸运
involved or hold yourself to a standard
使自己达到某种标准
as though there were not a huge amount
就好像没有那么多幸运一样
of luck involved it will drive you crazy
巨大的不公平会让你疯狂
totally unfairly the second thing is I
第二件事
don't read business books actually
我不读大多数的商务书
mostly I read The Economist every
我每周读经济学人
week but I mostly don't even read the
但我几乎不读新闻
news especially now it's driving me
尤其是最近的 这会让我疯狂
crazy you know what I spend time doing I
你知道我花时间做了什么 我和人们交谈
talk to people and I really listen to
我聆听他们说的
them the things that I was describing
them. The things that I was describing 我是在说在 X 是如何安排的
about how X is set up that's not taken
并不是从
from some great business book I read I'm
我读的商务书上获得
actually managing people and I'm really
事实上我管理这些人
paying attention to what moves their
我连驱动他们的微小事物都会关注
needle it's like this observation is
这就像在旁边
just watching people and saying like oh
看着别人做
I told you to do that and you're doing
说你这样做 你这样做
this why are you doing that you just go
你为什么要这样做？你只是去让他们做
ask them I have behaviors that you won't
你不会在商业书籍里面看到我的行为
read about in a business book but I
我也没有从商业书籍里面
didn't get them from a business book or
获得或收集他们的信息
any collection of them for example
any collection of them. For example, 例如 这是我的诫命之一
here's one of my mantras if you come
如果你进了我的办公室
into my office and you tell me I'm an
告诉我你是一个白痴
idiot I will say the first words out of
我会从嘴里说出的第一句话
my mouth will absolutely be thank you
绝对是感谢你
and very likely i will come around the
很可能会来到桌子旁
table and give you a hug because if you
给你一个拥抱
don't do that that will be the last time
因为如果你不这样做
that person ever says anything hard to
那可能是那个人最后一次向你说这种事
you and probably the last time anyone in
也可能是你最后一次从
the organization ever says anything hard
你的团队中听到这种事
and therefore important for you to know
你以后再也无法了解这样有价值的事了
to you but that's an observation about
但这是在观察人们以及他们如何正常运作的
humans and like what how they operate so
他们如何正常运作的
i strongly believe that there's a ton
所以我强烈认为
that can be learned from working hard
从努力工作中有很多可以学习的东西
being open to the fact that you're wrong
面对你长久以来都是错了的事实
a lot of the time because we're all
保持开放心态
wrong a lot of the time and really
因为我们长久以来都错了
listening to the people around you they
的确需要听从周围人的意见
have a lot to teach you so that doesn't
他们有很多可以教你的
mean never read any books but i think
所以我不是说不要读书
that the idea that you can somehow
我认为你可以通过合理的
program yourself by cleverly picking the
筛选你周围信息
one percent of the fire hose of data
的百分之一改善自己
that's coming at you and only listen to
当然只听从百分之一
that one percent is a bit of a fantasy
是一种有一点理想化的说法
thank you yeah my question is a little
谢谢 是的 我的问题和
bit in line with that so that's a
这个有点相关
fireside chats or personal questions
所以这就像人与人之间在炉边聊天是么？
okay I think so obviously you are you
我认为 很明显你[杂音]受到鼓舞
Jen spiration and very successful what
在你所做的事情上取得了很大成功
you are doing is there anything you had
有什么是
to stop doing or anything you had to
你必须停下来的
sacrifice during during that time
或者你不得不牺牲的？
yeah I mean I've certainly had to
是的 我是说我牺牲了很多
sacrifice a lot of things but a few of
其中一些对我来说
them that have been particularly hard
特别难 例如
for me for example I'm a people pleaser
成为是一个大家都喜欢的人
I like to resolve conflict and I'm
我喜欢解决冲突 我的身体 你知道
physically feel you know sick might be
会生病是一种夸张的说法
an exaggeration but uncomfortable when
但是与其他人对抗
people around me fight even if they work
会让我不舒服　即使他们为了我工作
for me I feel bad about it obviously
我也感觉不好 很明显
that's totally dysfunctional for me to
因为我无法和人直接冲突
be running an organization when I can't
这又对于我这样
be direct and have conflict with people
一个组织管理者是很重要的
it's really important that I'd be able
所以我能做这件事是很重要的
to do that so that's an example of
所以这有一个例子
something that I have learned how to do
当我有箴言或同事情感时
when I have mantras and structures for
我要如何去做
emotional structures that to get me to
事实上让我去做的话
do it and to do it quickly in fact but
就是赶快解决
it still doesn't feel very good when I
但当我这样做时
do it and that's the sort of thing I
我仍感觉不是很好
kind of wish I didn't come out
我希望我没有把书生气带出来
card-carrying nerd and yet I don't
事实上我并没有
actually spend very much in my time on
花很多时间在这些事上
those things that's another sacrifice I
这是我的另一个牺牲
want to end up actually tinkering and
我想快点实现这些想法
like thinking some the new stuff I'm an
想一些新的东西
entrepreneur I went to like actually run
我是一个企业家
one of the projects that X there's a
我想在 X 上运行一个项目
real sense in which I actually don't
real sense in which I actually don't 事实上我不想要
want the job that I have the reason that
我现在的工作了
I'm doing it is because I believe that
这样做的原因是我
I'm nurturing this group of people and
相信我在培养一群人
making something possible that wouldn't
这在其他地方是不可能发生的
be possible otherwise and that gives me
这给了我一个真实的目标
a real sense of purpose even though on a
即使在日常的基础上
day-to-day basis it's kind of not what
对我来说也不是有趣的
would be most fun for me so that's
所以这是另一个例子
another example thank you I Sebastian hi
谢谢 你好 Sebastian 你好 Astro
Astra I'm curious is if yes think that
我好奇的是 如果你认为
there is a opportunity to create a
有机会去建一家创业公司
start-up around I like a dating
譬如一个使用
application that uses machine learning
机器学习和 AI 的约会应用
aii because we all know divorce is like
因为我们都知道离婚在
a giant problem in our country but maybe
我们国家是一个巨大的问题
that uses like Google glass or something
或者说使用谷歌眼镜或其他东西
to create perfect mashes or do you think
能够建立更完美的匹配 或者 你认为...
I just have totally letting Sebastian
我完全赞同 Sebastian 回答这个问题
take this one great question haha
很棒的问题 哈哈
hey what was the question build it do
抱歉 问题是什么？ 建立它
you think like I start there could be
你认为 可以像 Tinder 那样
like a start-up like kind of like tender
使用使用机器学习
that uses machine learning in AI to
和AI可以创造一个完美的关系
create like perfect great relationship
所以你们未来就
so you can avoid divorce in the future
可以避免离婚了
I'm so let me let me let me just answer
所以 让我从不同角度回答一下
this differently the number of emails I
由于一些简单的原因
get forever stupid reason mostly from
我收到的大多数邮件都来自于德国
German stands out because there was in
表明因为德国的电视台
German television some futuristic show
一些人们新潮的设计
of people who build contraptions that
解决了天气变化
solve climate change and make clocks go
回过头看意义是巨大的
backwards is huge and sometimes right we
有些时候我们过于关注人们
nuts to see their people like spend so
在创造新事物上面所花费的精力
much time inventing things I look at
我看着他们并问
them and say why maybe I mean fixing
为什么？
divorces physical thing but what I often
我的意思是说离婚也许是一件好事
find is that people are taken by a
但我经常发现
technical idea they find oma whatever
人们常被技术所吸引
the sake combined i'm going to pull your
他们发现无论什么关系都可以联系起来
long to say you say tinder with machine
我把它拉长了和你说 你说使用机器学习的 Tinder
learning it's a technical idea but for
这是一个技术创意 但对我来说
me the first step is always to think
第一步是思考问题
about the problem so give an example on
举个例子
i have a lot of robotics colleagues some
我有很多机器人学家同事
very prominent one on the room here and
其中一些人很突出
any robotics professor takes the dogma
没有人会教条的认为世界上
that all problems in the world are
所有问题都可以用机器人解决
solved by robots right so you'd go for
对么？举个例子
example and would say I bit humanoid
我会说创造一个类人机器人
robots and what can they do well how
比如 做点什么呢
about elderly care all of Japanese
好吧 老人护理怎么样
robotics I have revenue does is like
我已经[杂音]做的所有日本机器人
that they have done it for 20 years put
像他们这样已经做了20年
a human robots because since the bidding
建立类人机器人
human items must be useful right and it
因为建立这样的人类机器人是有用的
must use for something so use for
对么 它必须对某事有用 适用于任何事
everything let me find the most useful
我发现的最有用的事是日常护理
thing is a daily care and incumbent
一家公司找到我
immunity a what do you think about if I
你认为我开一家两条腿的
can start a company on robots for
机器人老人护理公司的话
elderly care they have two legs and
有什么建议呢？
they're obviously that sounds great
很明显听起来不错
let's do one little excursion okay
让我们稍稍跑题一下
suppose you want to solve the elderly
假设你想解决一个老人护理产品项目的问题
care product project problem the ones
那么不论对象是什么
you want to solve
你都要想着去解决
whatever that one is let's think what's
让我们来想想这个问题
the best solution for that problem if it
最好的解决方法
still involves the robots inside your
它仍涉及到你公司的机器人 对吧？
company all right so suppose you're
所以假设你要去
going to solve the divorce problem in
解决你们国家的离婚问题
this country you really want to solve it
你真的想去解决它
went fewer divorces say for whatever
让离婚变少　不论出于什么原因
reason then let's take out what is the
让我们来思考一下这个问题最好的解决方案
best solution with this problem and if
如果你提出来在
you come I would think it's machine
Tinder 上应用机器学习
learning on tinder then did it oh yeah I
那么建立它
think that's a fine answer I would also
我认为这是一个很棒的答案
say that you know machine learning and
我也会这么说 你知道的
tinder might not make our list at X but
机器学习和 Tinder 可能不会在我们的X项目中
the general answer a text would be how
但一般在 X 中的项目会说
fast how long does it take for you to
你需要在这个项目里花多久
think about it and talk to people and
并与其他人讨论
how long does it take for you to make a
你需要多久才能制作一个原型呢？
prototype of it because if you can make
如果说你原型做的很快
a prototype of it really fast the right
那么正确的答案可能就是
answer might be don't worry about it
不用担心
just like make it and try it you'd be
尝试着做一下
amazed what making it and trying it like
你还会惊讶于你所做的和尝试的
maybe it's going to go supernova and you
就像超新星一样
don't have to have these arguments with
你不必有一个解决方案
idiots who don't understand it like us
我们就像其他人一样不了解这个事物
were maybe it turns out that it's
或者最终事实证明
actually not a good idea and then
这不是一个好的点子
that'll be the fastest way to discover
这是发现它不是一个好点子最快的方法
that it's not a good idea so that's not
所以这并不总是正确的事
always the right thing to do but that
但是你听起来
one sounds like you could prototype
原型化很快
something so fast that it might actually
但是你最起来可能会更快
be faster to just make it instead of
而不是要
trying to figure out whether you're
弄清楚你是对是错
right or not unfortunately really
不幸的是 我们马上要结束来了
unfortunately out of time in a few
只剩下几分钟了
seconds left absolutes in so bad really
seconds left. Astra it has been... Great. Astra已经... 很棒
thank you I want to end by saying that
谢谢你 我想以这个结尾
don't isn't that just so funny that's
别听只是娱乐一下 那确实是我正要说的
exactly what I was going to say so when
很早以前 当我在 X 开始时
i started at x a long time ago I
我向Sebastian报告了 他同意了
reported to Sebastian and he gave me so
所以他是我的领导
he was my manager and I really admire
我真的很尊敬你 Sebastian
you fashion and I just want to leave
我自己是想把这些人
these guys with something that I think
留在我想的地方
about and I know you said it
你知道这是个玩笑
tongue-in-cheek and I'm going to say it
我要说的是
partly to tease you but I also mean it
一半是要取笑你　但是我也很尊敬他们
sincerely to them and I know you meant
我知道你说真诚的意思
it sincerely Tim to me the first and
Sebastian是第一个
only really sincere feedback that
给我认真反馈的人
Sebastian ever gave me
正如我的主管一样
as my manager was don't listen to your
不要听你的主管
manager and and you were good at it and
你很擅长它
you were good at it and and and
想不到的是
ironically that was such important
这个反馈对我是如此的重要
feedback for me that it's really stuck
它让我坚持了下来
with me and it's part of why I admire
这也是我为什么尊敬你的原因
you thank you for being a guide for me
谢谢你引领我 引领我们
and for all of us my manager sits over
我的主管就坐在那
there and I can see how it's cringing
我可以看到他有多沮丧
request haha exactly what to do so thank
哈哈 是的
you sooo bad
谢谢你 Sebastian
you
谢谢你